Welcome to the Deep Dive, where we take your sources and extract the essential insights.
We act as your guides, navigating the information and finding those surprising
facts and critical connections you might otherwise miss.
Today's Deep Dive is based on a really candid conversation you shared with us,
excerpts from Katherine Pays' recent long-form interview on the Call Her Daddy YouTube channel.
Yeah, the source gives a pretty unique look behind the scenes of, well,
one of the most talked-about family vlogging channels, the Ace Family.
It really digs into its rise and eventual dissolution.
Right. Our mission today is to unpack the key points Katherine shared in this discussion,
finally shedding some light on some of the big questions that have surrounded them for so long.
You know, the relationship, their finances, all those controversies.
We're going to peel back the curtain on the rapid climb to fame and the very
personal struggles Katherine describes unfolding behind the scenes.
It's quite a journey she lays out.
Okay, let's unpack this. Katherine starts by sharing some
deeply personal details about her background. It really lays the foundation for who she became.
Yeah, she talks about her parents, immigrants from Nicaragua and Panama.
They met as teenagers, faced significant hardship.
She actually describes their relationship dynamic as quite toxic.
And what's striking is how she mentions her father being
a single dad for the first part of her childhood.
Exactly. And her mother making that really tough call to move to Florida,
believing it was for the family's best interests.
Katherine said even as a kid, she sort of understood her mom was doing the right thing.
And this early environment really shaped her perspective, especially around money.
She mentions here, and we don't have the money for that a lot.
Right. It created this powerful drive in her even from a young age.
She wanted to make a lot of money specifically to support her family, give them a distant life.
That financial stress, plus seeing her parents' difficult marriage.
How did that affect her view on relationships?
Well, she says it profoundly impacted her. It led her to really desire this
traditional till death, do us part kind of marriage.
She desperately wanted her own kids to grow up with both parents there,
that stability she felt she missed out on.
Okay, so with that background, she moves to LA.
And that's where Austin McBroom comes into the picture.
Yep, met him at an all white party, very LA, as you said.
He messaged her later. She thinks it was Twitter or something like that.
And she describes his feeling she had almost immediately.
A really significant inner knowing, she called it.
The moment she met him, even on their first date, she felt this certainty.
She was going to marry him, have kids with him.
Wow, on the first date, that's fantastic.
And credibly fast first kiss saying, I love you, same day.
But she said she wasn't nervous about it at all.
It just felt meant to be.
Like they could skip the whole dating phase because they just knew.
What was it about him that drew her in?
She liked his confidence, apparently.
That he didn't seem to care what other people thought.
And she saw him as motivated, very free with himself.
Said it reminded her of her brother.
And the speed didn't slow down, pregnant pretty quickly.
About two months in, yeah.
And the way she told him, memorable.
Through the positive pregnancy test,
stick at him while he was on the bed.
Oh, okay.
And the Ace Family Channel itself, how did that start?
It wasn't some master plan.
No, not at all.
It was actually Austin's friend who suggested it.
They had posted some homemade videos online.
They went viral on Facebook and the friend was like,
hey, you could actually make money from this.
And the timing was interesting too, right?
With Austin's basketball career.
Yeah, perfect timing in a way.
His NBA dreams had sort of fizzled out that summer.
Basketball wasn't a clear path anymore.
So starting YouTube suddenly looked like a viable alternative.
So their first daughter, Elle, is born and putting her online.
How did they decide that?
Catherine says it just felt natural.
Their initial intentions, she insists,
were pure just sharing their journey
as this young family starting out.
No hesitation about putting the kids online back then.
Initially, no.
She felt like they were almost pioneering
that kind of family vlogging,
especially as social media was becoming this monster,
as she put it.
But then came the criticism, the accusations of exploiting the kids.
Right.
And she addresses that directly.
She maintains their initial intentions
were good in making a living while being present parents.
And it's fascinating, she points out
their most popular videos early on weren't the big stunts,
but just simple family moments,
like them sitting on the floor.
That's interesting.
And do they handle the kids' earnings responsibly?
She confirms they set up separate bank accounts
for the children very early, around 2017.
Elle was only about a year old then.
And looking back now, her perspective
on sharing kids online.
It's pretty nuanced.
She doesn't think there's a definite right or wrong.
Ultimately, she feels everything happens
the way it's meant to.
Kind of a fatalistic view, maybe.
Okay, let's shift to the financial side
of this massive success.
They were making serious money.
Serious is an understatement.
She reveals at their peak,
they were pulling in seven figures.
A month.
Wow.
How did she even process that?
That's, I think she says she felt numb,
sort of disattached from it,
like it wasn't quite real.
And looking back now,
she expresses a lot of regret.
Bad business decisions, having yes men around.
Wishing she'd invested differently.
Helped your parents more.
Exactly.
It really highlights how getting that huge financial goal
didn't automatically equal happiness,
especially when it came from something
with so much pressure attached.
And that pressure changed how they approached content, right?
Definitely.
She describes this shift from filming parts of their life
to feeling like they were living to film.
Everything became about the next big reveal,
the clickbait surprise.
She used the phrase clown in a circus.
Yeah, feeling like she had to perform
these surprise reactions for the camera,
rather than just genuinely experiencing moments together.
Was there a specific moment she realized
how much strain this was causing?
She talks about her second daughter's birth,
feeling disconnected,
not really wanting to film it,
but feeling this obligation
because the audience was waiting.
It even made her question if Austin was truly present
or just focused on getting the shot.
And that bled into other things.
Yeah.
Like wondering if his romantic gestures were real
or just for show.
Were they genuine or for the camera?
And then feeling she had to give
this big theatrical reaction back.
She admits they just didn't communicate
about boundaries, about what should stay private.
This lack of partnership seems to have extended to money, too.
According to her, yes.
Big time.
She describes Austin making huge financial decisions,
six figures sometimes disappearing from accounts
without even talking to her about it.
Like what kind of decisions?
Paying for private jets, things like that,
stuff she says she wouldn't have chosen herself,
things that weren't priorities for her before him.
That must have caused a lot of tension.
She says it was heartbreaking.
It caused immense stress in the relationship.
How did he react when she brought it up?
Apparently often dismissive,
like, I'm sorry, I just didn't want you to worry.
But for her, marriage meant tackling these big issues together,
things affecting their kids, their future.
It wasn't just about shielding her.
Which brings us to the house foreclosure.
Very public, very symbolic.
Yeah, by then she felt like she was losing control
over everything, family, relationship, career.
The house was the one thing she was desperately trying
to hold onto as something stable.
And she found out.
How?
Completely out of the blue.
Her father-in-law called her,
Catherine, the house is under foreclosure.
It's all over the news.
Just like that.
But she thought she was paying the mortgage.
She said she was paying it every month for three years.
She was totally confused.
The reasons given were technical.
The loan type ended.
It was a jumbo loan, no certificate of occupancy.
But it didn't make sense to her.
The impact on her must have been immense.
Devastating.
She said she cried in ocean.
Losing the house broke her more than anything else.
It represented that feeling of home, of security
she'd been seeking her whole life.
Losing it felt like losing the last anchor.
And behind the scenes during all this chaos,
what was life like?
She describes feeling like she was constantly pretending,
deeply disconnected from herself in a really dark place,
barely going out, not seeing friends or family much.
And all the while,
these cheating rumors about Austin are swirling online.
Constantly, her initial reaction, her heart sank.
She even found herself wondering if he physically had the time to cheat,
remembering some saying about men always having time.
Did she see evidence herself?
She mentions getting random specific texts while he was right beside her.
It made it incredibly hard to know what was real and what wasn't.
So a mix of true, false, distorted information.
Exactly, just creating total confusion for her.
And she says she did confront him about the allegations early on.
What was his response back then?
Basically that it comes with the territory of being famous,
that they shouldn't respond because it would just make it worse.
And she says at that point, she trusted him.
She followed his lead.
Did she believe he was cheating right from the very start of the rumors?
No, she actually says she doesn't think he was cheating
right at the beginning when those first allegations surfaced.
Okay, so when did that shift happen?
When did suspicion turn into knowing?
She pinpoints a key moment.
The, oh shit, he's cheating realization.
It was after Austin went to Miami for a supposed meeting.
Their second daughter was only about six months old.
Did she question him going?
Not really.
She mentions her personality is usually trusting, giving partners freedom,
which she notes really contrasted with her mom's reaction,
who was like, why are you letting him go with such a young baby?
What happened while he was in Miami?
He accidentally pocket dialed her.
She heard women's voices in the background.
At the time, she kind of brushed it off like, okay,
I guess he's hanging out with women and hung up.
Didn't seem like a huge deal then.
But then something else came up later.
Months later, yeah.
A blonde male makeup artist posted a YouTube video,
and it had specific details about Austin, other women,
and a boat trip that same weekend in Miami.
And Catherine saw this video while she was secretly pregnant with their son.
Oh, wow.
How did she react to seeing that video?
Total breakdown.
Balling her eyes out, she said.
Questioning everything, was it true?
Was she being stupid?
Should she just try to keep the peace for the family?
She did confront Austin about that video.
And his reaction.
Denial.
Claim the guy was trying to extort him.
But Catherine says, deep down, she knew something was really wrong.
She just actively lied to herself, she was pregnant,
wanted to protect that little piece of peace they had left.
She also mentioned a dream around this time.
Yeah, really vivid.
A beautiful blonde woman turning into a demon on her bed,
woke up crying, felt eerie all day.
Very symbolic, right?
Definitely.
And that same day, something else happened, something concrete.
Yes.
They were filming for Vlogmas, at a salon,
getting their daughter's first haircut,
fans around, cameras rolling, the whole setup.
Her phone died.
She asked to use Austin's phone just to take a picture.
And she stresses she had never looked in his phone before, ever.
And then what?
The second she grabbed it,
a long text message popped right up on the screen from a woman.
And the content, what she quickly saw,
clearly implied an emotional relationship,
something like, if you really loved your wife.
Oh my god, in that moment.
Her heart just dropped, felt totally surreal,
like she wasn't on earth anymore.
And she's pregnant, people are watching, the cameras on her.
Did anyone else see it?
Their assistant saw it too.
Austin immediately grabbed the phone back
and deleted the message right there.
And for Catherine, that was it.
Oh my gosh, it's true, no more doubt.
How did she handle that, right then and there?
Somehow she kept calm, finished filming at the salon.
But in the car on the way home, she confronted him quietly
because the kids were there.
He was just evasive, it's nothing.
Look back home.
Full breakdown, yelling, screaming, begging him for the truth.
Feeling so stupid, she said,
because she'd been pregnant and ignoring her gut feeling for so long.
What did she do?
Ran out of the house, just drove around crying aimlessly,
ended up parking at a park, just praying,
God, if you hear me, please tell me what to do.
Did you feel like she got an answer?
She describes hearing this clear voice,
telling her to be strong for her son,
steal a name she already knew she'd use.
The voice told her not to make impulsive decisions,
just keep going, it would all make sense later.
So she went back home.
Yeah, decided to just act like nothing for a couple of days.
She said it was the longest they'd ever gone
without speaking since they met.
And after those couple of days, did they talk?
Yes, in the car again.
He finally told her who the woman from the text message was.
Did they clarify things?
It made things all make sense, she said.
She remembered him previously mentioning
helping some woman with Snapchat,
and it all clicked into place.
The lies, the denials.
And her reaction then, after he admitted it.
Surprisingly, maybe her first instinct was still forgiveness.
She felt he was maybe crying out for help.
That traditional view of marriage sticking by her husband
was still really strong.
Was this round the time they went to Hawaii?
Yeah, that trip was suggested for healing,
supposedly because Hawaii is the heart chakra of the planet,
a spiritual attempt to fix things.
And she announced her pregnancy from there.
She did.
She felt like she was carrying this huge secret
about the marriage falling apart
and just wanted to scream the truth but couldn't.
Announcing the pregnancy felt like
the only thing she could share publicly.
Looking back, she realized her focus was always on fixing it.
Always, how can we fix this?
Like it was a business problem, not this deep emotional betrayal.
She was so focused on trying to stay by him,
she wasn't really letting herself feel her own pain.
And Austin's reaction during all this, was he apologetic?
She says it never felt genuinely apologetic to her.
Not really.
And get this, she says he never actually uttered the words
I cheated to her until literally about a week before
this Call Her Daddy interview came out.
Wow.
Only when her book chapter detailing it was published.
Exactly.
She said finally hearing him say it, admit it,
was actually healing for her.
It was validation.
Proof she wasn't crazy after all those denials.
Why do you think he finally admitted it then, publicly?
She speculates maybe because the book called him out directly
or maybe he finally understood the bigger picture,
the consequences.
She also pushes back hard on something he claimed recently.
Oh yeah.
His claim in a video that she was basically
okay with it as long as you don't embarrass me.
She says that is absolutely not true and deeply hurtful.
Because it shifts the blame, avoids accountability.
Precisely.
She emphasizes she would never say that and it's not what she
teach her kids about relationships or cheating.
Did she confirm other affairs besides the one link to the text?
Yes.
She confirmed knowing about multiple women.
She specifically said she's for sure aware of three.
Okay.
And what about some of those really specific viral rumors
that Tana Mojo lipstick story?
Catherine believes Kanna's account is true
and she feels Tana covering for him basically confirmed it for her back then.
She was hurt.
Tana didn't tell her directly though.
The rumor about hiring nannies to sleep with.
False she says.
They never even had a nanny.
The yacht orgy rumor in Miami.
That one she says she got confirmation about years later
through a friend whose husband was actually there on the yacht that weekend.
Whoa.
And bringing his mistress to their own charity event at the Staple Center.
She confirms that's true.
Says it was the same woman from the text message incident.
A huge public betrayal.
Austin denied that one publicly, right?
He did.
Catherine sees that as him just trying to control the narrative
because it makes him look terrible doing that at a family event they were hosting.
But she insists it absolutely happened.
A family member of his even confirmed telling him not to bring that girl.
It was a big moment for her confirming the extent of the lies.
So with all this going on,
what happened to their intimacy, their sex life?
She explains that once she knew about the cheating,
she just checked out emotionally and physically.
She felt her body was a temple
and refused intimacy when there was no honesty between them.
For how long?
Essentially no intimacy for maybe four or five years.
Spanning postpartum periods, the allegations, pregnancies.
A long time.
Did she take any responsibility for that lack of intimacy?
She does.
She takes full accountability for not having serious talks about it
or seeking therapy together to address it.
But ultimately, the cheating was the final straw.
Absolutely.
She says that was the breaking point.
The marriage couldn't survive that level of betrayal.
And Austin's bizarre claim about her thinking she was the virgin Mary
reincarnated as the reason for no sex.
Yeah, she addressed that, calls it really hurtful,
and just the strange thing to say.
She sees it as him just throwing jabs,
trying to make her look crazy by twisting her spirituality,
her connection to Christ and Mother Mary,
into something weird or delusional.
Why did she keep all this secret for so long?
Not confide in anyone.
Several reasons.
She didn't want to change how people saw Austin initially.
She still held on to hope they could heal privately,
and she genuinely believes gossiping is poison.
So she didn't tell family until she decided on divorce.
Right.
Only told her parents and family when she knew for sure she wanted out.
But keeping it inside must have been incredibly difficult.
She admits it was eating her alive,
but eventually it felt like everybody knows anyway,
as things became more obvious publicly.
That pressure of keeping up appearances.
Huge impact on her,
feeling like she was in a fishbowl,
performing this happy family image
while living a completely different reality.
It sounds like a massive internal conflict.
Protect the image, the kid's stability.
Yeah.
Versus telling your truth.
Exactly.
Her priority was always being a mother first.
The thought of creating two homes,
figuring out a new livelihood, it was overwhelming.
Plus, being a content creator,
couple added another layer.
And the hardest part was his denial to her.
Yeah, because if he wouldn't admit it to her privately,
he'd never admit it publicly.
She felt completely gaslighted,
knowing the truth but being told she was wrong.
She mentioned the public judgment too.
People just judge on the surface,
she said, without knowing the full story.
And another reason for silence.
Not wanting to hurt him or the fans.
Yeah.
She didn't want to break the family in that public way,
disappoint millions of fans.
And she didn't want to see Austin face that humiliation.
She thought she could handle her own pain,
but maybe not his public scrutiny.
Ironic because he got the scrutiny anyway
and she realized she had to stop living the lie for herself.
So the final, final breaking point.
When did she know, okay, this is it, I have to leave now.
She describes a conversation right before one of Austin's boxing matches.
She finally said, I'm not happy.
His response.
Dismissive.
Told her not to bring it up with the fight so close.
Then he got sick right before the fight.
Yeah, 103 fever.
She saw it as symbolic, a message like a mirror of their internal chaos.
What about the fight itself?
Watching him get knocked down repeatedly but keep getting up.
It gave her this thought, this is who he is,
he always stands up when he falls.
She felt she heard a voice say it was an ego death for him
and she needed to hold space for him.
So even then still feeling protective?
In a way, in the ambulance afterward he was disoriented.
The next day she posted that picture holding his hand.
She explained it wasn't romantic love
but showing she was still there for him as family as a team.
No matter what I will always stand by his side.
But that moment also clarified something else for her.
Yes, it solidified she was okay being a family team
but they weren't really a team because the lies were still there.
He wasn't being honest.
When did the, it has to be 9W realization hit?
On her 33rd birthday.
A year she'd always felt would be significant.
That day she booked her flight for that spiritual retreat in Brazil.
That booking was the decision she says,
even if the words weren't spoken yet.
The separation felt inevitable in the air.
Okay, so the actual divorce conversation, when and how?
Right when she got back from Brazil.
She described the retreat as this massive expansive experience.
She got in the car with Austin at the airport.
And just told him.
Pretty directly.
It's not a secret that our relationship is done and we're both unhappy.
I want a divorce.
His reaction.
Okay.
She felt relief, even happiness.
Wanted to work on an exit plan together, keep it amicable.
Interestingly, his realtor had just sent him a listing
for a rental house down the street.
He saw it as interesting how life works.
They didn't do a joint announcement video though.
Why not?
Catherine felt if he couldn't be truthful off camera,
he wouldn't be truthful on camera about the real reasons,
especially the cheating.
She was willing to own her mistakes,
but he wasn't ready to be honest about his infidelity.
So she suggested a written statement.
Yeah, but he wanted a video offered to show it to her first.
She waited a month.
When she finally saw it, she felt it was social suicide for him,
just going around the truth, not vulnerable at all.
She told him she didn't like it.
And then something really disturbing happened.
She believes he secretly recorded her reaction
while she was watching that video and telling him she didn't like it.
You recorded her without consent?
Yes.
She feels he made the video knowing she wouldn't approve
and recorded her reaction purposefully, maybe to use later.
She calls it manipulative and illegal.
Wow.
Okay.
She also talked about using ayahuasca.
She did.
So she started during that really dark period,
marriage problems, losing the house, scams, all of it.
Was she doing it alone?
Her brother had used it for years and was supportive.
She described one ceremony leading to a full Kundalini awakening,
helping her remember things, changing her life.
She sees it as a very powerful tool.
Austin made claims about that too, right?
About the kids being there.
Yes, he claimed the kids were home during ceremonies.
She calls that a lie, deeply hurtful,
and another jab at something sacred to her.
Things people throw stones at things they don't understand.
Does she ever use it with Austin?
Or did others express concern?
No, never used it with him.
And she says no one close to her has ever expressed concern about her use.
And the weirdest claim that she turned him into a mermaid?
Huh, yeah.
She finds that funny now.
This explains it was just for a mermaid themed photo shoot
for her skincare line launch in Hawaii.
Just a fun shoot.
So why would he say that?
She thinks because people were making fun of the photos online already,
he just jumped on it to extra painter look crazy.
Another attempt to discredit her.
So fast forward, she's moved on, new relationship.
Yes, met her new partner Igor on that same Rizzo retreat,
middle of the Amazon, she said.
And she's open about the timeline now.
Very.
She owns it, she says.
Emphasizes her relationship with Austin was emotionally and intimately over
for years before she met Igor.
That's important context.
What was her mindset going into that retreat?
Was she looking for someone?
Quite the opposite.
I felt she had too much baggage.
Three kids, public figure, thought she'd be alone forever,
wasn't looking to date.
But she'd reached a point of feeling complete and whole in herself.
Relationship or not.
And the retreat changed that perspective.
Realized the baggage was all in my head.
Meeting Igor started is just friendship within that experience.
Never expected more.
How does she describe the new relationship?
Says she's never felt so safe, feels she really earned it
after everything she went through.
How do Austin and Igor get along?
Or seem to?
She can't speak for Austin's real feelings.
But she notes his public gestures, like getting Igor a stepfather shirt.
Kind of hard to read.
And has she met Austin's new partner?
Yes, about a year ago.
Says she likes her, trusts her kids, judgment and how they interact with her.
Doesn't judge their journey, basically.
Wow.
That is an incredible amount to process.
It really gives so much depth and context to a story that played out so publicly.
Yeah, from that dizzying rise to fame,
built on this image of a perfect family,
to the really profound struggles hidden underneath the finances, the infidelity.
It paints such a picture of that internal conflict she faced, right?
Trying to keep up the public image versus her private reality,
the tool it took on her sense of self.
Absolutely.
And then her incredibly difficult path towards healing,
finding her own voice, and ultimately a new beginning.
Her final message in the interview was about forgiveness.
Yeah, just forgiveness is key.
Simple but powerful given everything she described.
Her whole story just makes you think about the complexities, doesn't it?
The potential cost of that kind of public life,
how incredibly hard it must be to navigate trauma when everyone's watching.
And the strength it takes to break away from a situation,
even a painful one that feels familiar or safe.
It also shows how different people react, staying, leaving,
protecting the family image above all else.
It really leaves you with a potent thought to mull over, doesn't it?
In this age of constant sharing,
how does that pressure to maintain a perfect public image
actually change how we experience and how we respond to
our own private, often really messy, crises?