Welcome to the Deep Dive.
Today, we're plunging into quite a sack of sources,
social media, news reports, YouTube,
medical opinions, all swirling around one,
while truly unforgettable, viral event.
The woman who used Gorilla Glue spray in her hair.
Our mission here is to take all these pieces,
try to untangle the, frankly, chaotic sequence of events,
explore the really intense public reactions,
and, maybe most importantly, uncover
the completely unexpected twist that came out of it all.
Let's unpack this.
Yeah, it's one of those stories
that start almost like internet absurdity, didn't it?
But when you really dig into the sources,
it gets much more complex.
It highlights some, well, fascinating,
and sometimes pretty troubling things
about our online world.
Absolutely.
So let's set the scene.
This all kicks off with Tessica Brown.
She's a 40-year-old woman from Louisiana.
And it's February 3rd.
She uploads his TikTok, right?
Showing her hair pulled back, really tight ponytail.
And her explanation, at least according to her video,
was that she ran out of her normal stuff,
got to be glue spray,
which people use for, like, extreme hold.
Yeah, that's a known product for that kind of thing.
Exactly.
And she grabs Gorilla Glue spray instead,
thinking somehow it would just hold the style.
Right, not just any glue,
but, you know, industrial adhesive.
Not for hair.
And the immediate problem,
well, it was exactly what you might fear.
Her hair was just cemented,
completely stuck to her head, unmovable.
She even said in that first video,
and this quote really stuck,
my hair has been like this for about a month now.
It's not a choice.
A month.
A whole month.
Can you imagine the discomfort?
Yeah.
Just, wow.
And her attempts to fix it, they got pretty desperate.
She mentioned washing it, what, 15 times.
15 times, yeah.
And nothing.
Follow-up videos showed her getting really frustrated,
you know, trying different things, even in tears.
And that vulnerability, that visible struggle,
I think that's probably what made it go
so incredibly viral, so fast.
Oh, definitely.
It just struck a chord.
On one hand, you had total confusion,
disbelief, you know, the,
why would you even do that reaction?
But the source is, it wasn't just that,
there was also this weird mix of like dark humor,
but also some real empathy starting to bubble up.
People saw the distress,
even if the initial choice seemed baffling.
That sort of reaction storm confusion,
amusement, sympathy, it's classic viral fuel.
And once it blew up, oh man,
the device started pouring in from commenters.
We saw everything.
Some sounded vaguely plausible,
like soaking her head in alcohol and water.
Someone mentioned a specific 25% alcohol mix.
Right, 75% water, and then other stuff.
Coconut oil, tea tree oil, olive oil,
even like physically trying to pry it apart
with a fork or something.
Yeah, and importantly, a nurse did chime in, apparently,
warning her not to just pour alcohol on her head,
but to apply it carefully.
Which, you know, shows how quickly
bad advice can spread right alongside
the good intentions online.
Good point.
Viral advice isn't always vetted advice.
So she tried some of it.
Sources say she did the coconut and tea tree oil thing
overnight, wrapped her head in plastic, didn't work.
So the next logical step, professional help.
She entered by going to the ER
at St. Bernard Parish Hospital.
That was February 6th.
And this is where it gets interesting,
because even the medical pros were a bit thrown.
Sources say the nurses there tried acetone.
Now, a dermatologist later said
acetone could potentially work on the adhesive.
Right, I saw that video.
Yeah, but for Tessica, it apparently just burned her scalp,
made the glee kind of gooey for a second,
and then it just hardened right back up.
So not the quick fix anyone was hoping for.
We saw that dermatologist Dr. Dustin Portella
weigh in around February 5th.
He mentioned acetone, yeah,
but warned it could be irritating, drying.
He also suggested maybe a professional salon
or seeing a dermatologist if the irritation got bad.
And he floated Gugan as like a last resort, maybe.
But caution heavily, it's not meant for skin,
only carefully on the hair if acetone failed.
It just shows how unique this situation was.
Experts were having the sort of brainstorm solutions
on the fly.
Exactly, it's that challenge of the digital age, isn't it?
Something totally unprecedented goes viral,
and suddenly everyone's throwing out ideas,
experts, and amateurs alike.
Totally.
And while she's dealing with all this physical stuff,
the media frenzy is just exploding.
That first TikTok got insane views, like immediately.
By February 8th, it's national news, TMZ is all over it.
Of course.
Even celebrities started talking about it.
Chance the Rapper tweeted something supportive,
basically saying maybe she genuinely didn't realize
how bad it would be, and it was hard to laugh
seeing her actual distress.
That amplification is just massive, isn't it?
A mistake shared online becomes this huge global thing
in like two days.
And the public reaction really split.
You had a lot of sympathy, definitely.
People were suggesting maybe she mixed it up
with Gorilla Snot Edge Control.
Similar name used for hair.
Right, the name similarity is definitely there.
People were saying it could have been an honest mistake.
But then you had the other side.
Pretty harsh criticism.
Questioning her intelligence, pointing out she's 40,
the warning labels are obvious.
Some people even thought the whole thing was stage.
Yeah, the planned for clout argument,
people asking things like,
well, why aren't her hands stuck too if she sprayed it?
And someone countered the Gorilla Snot idea
by pointing out it comes in a squeeze bottle,
not a spray can like the glue she used.
But that detail just added more fuel
to the online debate, you know.
Mistakers don't.
Even the company, Gorilla Glue,
put out a statement around February 8th.
They basically said they felt bad about it,
hoped she got good medical care,
and gently reminded everyone
their product isn't for hair.
Right, trying to distance themselves a bit.
But understandably.
Meanwhile, in the middle of all this,
Tessica starts to go fund me.
That was February 7th.
And it took off, raised over $23,000 really fast.
Oh, wow.
Which, again, sparked more conversation.
Especially because she started using the name
Gorilla Glue Girl herself
in like a YouTube video title that same day.
That's interesting, kind of claiming the narrative
while still going through it.
It's a very modern thing,
that rapid shift to owning the viral identity.
Definitely.
But okay, back to the actual glue problem.
Home remedies failed, the ER couldn't quite crack it.
The sources show it became clear
she needed something more serious,
like surgical intervention.
On February 9th, she announced
she was going to see a surgeon.
And this is where Dr. Michael Obang
enters the story out in Los Angeles.
According to TMZ reports around the 9th,
he saw her situation online,
realized how bad it was,
and made this incredible offer to do the surgery
to free her scalp for free.
That's amazing.
Saved her something like $12,500, the report said.
Yeah.
So the surgery happened on February 11th.
And based on the footage, it looked pretty intense.
Surgeons carefully, gradually unsticking the hair.
Dr. Obang had figured out the main chemical was polyurethane,
so they used specific solvents designed to dissolve that.
He apparently even tried reaching out to gorilla glue
to see if they had any special removers,
didn't get through directly, it seems.
And Dr. Obang's description really hit home
how bad it was.
He called it no joke.
Talked about the hair damage,
the constant pulling on her scalp,
how she couldn't sleep properly.
He said it was like having a stick stuck to your head.
Just constant discomfort and anxiety.
She apparently needed medication before the surgery
just to handle the stress.
So it wasn't just cosmetic.
It was genuinely causing physical and mental anguish.
Absolutely.
Which makes the footage from right after the surgery
on the 11th so striking.
You see her relief checking out her hair, finally free.
Dr. Obang mentioned follow-ups, pain meds,
but the glue was gone.
Must have been an incredible feeling
after a solid month of that ordeal.
You'd think, okay, story over, right.
She's free, she can move on.
But the aftermath had more drama.
The very next day, February 12th,
merch drops, t-shirts with her picture
or like a cartoon gorilla glue can
and the slogan bonded for life.
Oof.
Yeah, that didn't land well with everyone.
The backlash was pretty swift.
A lot of the sympathy seemed to evaporate overnight.
People were criticizing her hard
for trying to profit off it.
Comments like just no or really harsh ones
like write a book on how important reading is.
That sense of betrayal again.
We were rooting for you, now you're selling merch.
Yeah, and suggestions to donate the money instead.
Maybe to charities providing wigs for cancer patients,
things like that.
Some people flat out said they were unfollowing her.
It was a sharp turn in public opinion.
But she responded quickly to that criticism.
On February 13th, she announced
she was donating $20,000 from the GoFundMe.
Remember, it raised over 23K
to Dr. Obang's non-profit foundation, Restore,
which is reconstructive surgery.
Okay, that's significant.
And she said the rest would go to three local families.
She posted a picture with Dr. Obang thanking him,
saying he gave me my life back.
And that move, donating most of the money,
probably did a lot to counter the profiting narrative.
It showed gratitude and an intention to give back,
which definitely complicated things for the critics.
Yeah, it added nuance back into the story.
There were also some lingering legal things
floating around.
Remember those early reports she might sue, Gorilla Glue?
Right, though our sources didn't really
confirm that panning out.
No, but her lawyer did apparently send
a cease and desist letter to some blogger
who was claiming the whole story was fake.
The lawyer confirmed, nope, it was real.
Which just goes to show,
even when something is documented like this,
people will still call it fake online.
And sometimes you need lawyers to push back, it's wild.
So, trying to move past it all,
on February 17th, she posted pics of a new haircut.
Short.
And the caption was, I am not my hair.
Thinking supporters, saying the good outweigh the bad overall.
And the reaction to the haircut seemed mostly positive.
Yeah, generally, like fresh start, looks cute,
you can rock short styles.
People seemed ready to see her move on, visually at least.
A physical change signaling,
maybe a new chapter after all that public chaos.
But the story didn't just end with her,
the ripple spread.
Its sheer virality seemed to,
well, inspire others, not always in a good way.
Yes, the copycat effect.
A really dark side of viral fame,
where people try to replicate the attention,
sometimes dangerously.
Like Len Martin, the guy in Baton Rouge.
Oh right, he apparently tried to prove
the glue wasn't that strong.
By gluing a red solo cup to his lip.
Around February 16th.
Yes, and predictably he ended up in the ER
because he couldn't get it off.
He was quoted saying something like,
this is definitely not one to try,
under statement of the year.
And the reaction was way less sympathetic than for Tessica.
Mostly just comments about stupidity.
Pretty much.
And then there was Avani Reyes,
another TikToker who also claims
she put gorilla glue in her hair.
Showed videos struggling to comb it,
even one from a hospital waiting room
saying her scalp was burning.
But a story got murky, didn't it?
People accused her of doing it for clout,
wasting hospital time during COVID.
Exactly, and her GoFundMe situation
was really confusing.
There were reports of donations,
even a big $3,000 one.
But then she apparently claimed the GoFundMe
was just a prank.
The big donation wasn't real
and insisted she wasn't a scammer.
So based on the sources,
it's kind of hard to tell if her situation was even real
or just an attempt to ride the viral wave.
Which is a whole other cautionary tale
about online content.
Definitely.
These cases, real or maybe staged,
just show how powerful and potentially harmful
these viral trends can be,
sparking dangerous imitations.
And it wasn't just imitations,
there were also people trying to actively debunk
Tessica's original story.
Like that YouTuber, December Reed, on February 10th.
Right, they sprayed the glue on hair extensions,
let it dry, used Goof Off,
and claimed it came right out, didn't really soak in.
But the comments section pushed back hard on that, right?
People argued maybe the glue needed water
to activate properly, or it needed way longer,
like 24 hours, or Tessica's whole month,
or maybe blow-drying it changed things.
Yeah, lots of counterarguments.
So even with videos trying to show it wasn't that bad,
a lot of people still seemed convinced
Tessica's story might have been faked anyway.
It just shows how sticky a narrative can be online.
Once people believe something,
it's hard to shake, even with counter-evidence.
It might help, though,
to quickly touch on hair glue in general,
because using some kind of glue
isn't totally unheard of professionally.
Good point.
Like, medical-grade adhesives are used
for weaves, wigs, extensions sometimes?
Yeah, there are different methods.
Strand by strand, which takes ages, like six to eight hours,
or using wefted panels, which is faster.
And even those proper hair glues
can sometimes slip or fail, right?
Like if you sweat a lot or use oily products.
Correct, but, and this is the crucial point,
the sources are crystal clear,
gorilla glue, the industrial stuff,
absolutely not something used for hair, ever.
So circling back to Tessica's initial mistake,
while it doesn't excuse using it,
you can maybe see a sliver
of how the confusion could happen.
The spray bottle looks like hairspray.
There's that gorilla snot stuff for edges.
Her usual product was got-to-be glued.
It's a confluence of, like,
visual and name similarities.
It doesn't make it right,
but maybe explains the initial split-second grab
for the wrong can in a moment
of running out of her usual stuff.
Maybe?
Maybe.
But ultimately, the big, loud takeaway
from all the sources is just
read the warning labels,
double-check what you're putting on your body,
sounds basic,
but this whole saga shows
the potentially severe consequences
when that step gets skipped.
A very public, very painful lesson learned there.
Okay, so we've covered the mistake,
the virality, the medical drama,
the copycats, the context,
but here's where the story takes
just an absolutely mind-bending turn.
Something that happened
after the glue nightmare was mostly over.
Right, this part is,
well, it feels almost unbelievable,
just the timing of it all.
So after the glue situation was resolved,
Tessago was planning a totally separate thing,
a mommy makeover.
Reports on February 27th
mentioned breast lift implants.
And guess who her pre-surgery consultant
was for this procedure?
Dr. Michael Obang,
the same surgeon who freed her hair
just weeks earlier.
Exactly, and here's the twist.
During the routine physical exam
for the breast surgery,
just earlier that week,
Dr. Obang found a lump...
Yeah.
...in each breast.
Wow, just didn't, wow.
A chance finding
during an unrelated consultation.
A mammogram then confirmed
there were masses.
And the sources say
she's already had surgery to remove them
and they were being tested for cancer
at the time of reporting.
That's genuinely astonishing.
A terrible mistake
leads her to a specific doctor
who, weeks later,
in a completely different context,
makes a potentially life-saving discovery.
It's incredible.
Tessago herself has quoted
saying she felt like the whole
gorilla glue thing
was somehow supposed to lead to this moment.
And you can imagine how that resonated online.
The public reaction to this news
was totally different.
Just aw, really, people saying
everything happens for a reason.
The glue fiasco saved her.
Crazy how the universe works.
God is looking after her.
Yeah, it completely reframed the narrative,
didn't it?
From a bizarre mistake
to something...
maybe profound.
It really did.
So stepping back,
what does this all really mean?
We dove into this story
that started as, you know,
a shocking but seemingly
simple mistake on TikTok.
It blew up into internet fame,
caused real pain,
sparked huge debates,
needed surgery,
even inspired copycats.
It really is a microcosm
of our digital age, isn't it?
How fast personal stuff
gets broadcast, judged,
amplified, copied,
generating both incredible support
and waves of criticism
and just plain bad information.
And then the truly wild part.
Yeah.
The sources show
how this viral mess
potentially led directly
to a critical,
maybe life-saving medical find.
It just highlights
the completely unpredictable
ways life can unfold.
How unforeseen events,
even negative ones,
can have these profound
unexpected consequences.
The whole journey
just brings up so many questions,
doesn't it,
about like information literacy,
critical thinking
when everything's going viral,
the sheer power of social media
for both good and bad
and just the strange,
complex ways people react
and cope.
Absolutely.
So looking at this whole rollercoaster,
here's something maybe
for you, the listener,
to think about.
In our world,
where stories like Tesicas
can explode overnight,
do you think they ultimately
make us more skeptical,
more critical of the stuff
we see online?
Or do they just end up
encouraging more people
to chase that viral fame
no matter what the risk might be?
Yeah.
That's a heavy question.
Definitely something to ponder
next time you're scrolling.
Thanks for joining us
for this deep dive.