Pauline Parker and Juliet Hume, the friendship that led to murder. The world of crime has seen
its fair share of chilling partnerships, but few are as infamous as the one shared by Pauline
Parker and Juliet Hume. These two schoolgirls from New Zealand shocked the nation in 1954,
when their intense friendship culminated in the brutal murder of Pauline's mother,
Honora Parker. When they were both in their early teens, though from different backgrounds,
they quickly became inseparable. Pauline was the daughter of a working-class family. While Juliet
came from a more privileged background her father, Henry Hume was a noted physicist and
rector of the University of Canterbury. Juliet had a cosmopolitan upbringing. Having lived in
England and South Africa before settling in New Zealand, both girls were intelligent,
academically bright, and shared a passion for literature and fantasy worlds. What drew them
together, however, was more than just common interests. Both girls had experienced illnesses
that left them somewhat isolated from their peers Pauline suffered from osteomyelitis,
a painful bone infection, and Juliet had suffered bots of tuberculosis.
This isolation fostered a deep bond between them, a connection that quickly grew into something
intense and all-consuming, a fantasy world of their own. As their friendship blossomed,
Pauline and Juliet created a rich fantasy world, which they called the fourth world. It was a place
where they could escape the mundane reality of their everyday lives and indulge in elaborate
fantasies of romance, adventure, and grandeur. They wrote stories, poems, and plays set in this
imaginary world drawing inspiration from historical figures and film stars. Their bond became more
than just friendship. It was almost like a shared identity. The intensity of their relationship
began to concern those around them. The girls' parents and teachers noticed how they withdrew
from others, spending all their time together, wrapped up in their elaborate fantasies.
Some speculated that the relationship was romantic, though there was little
concrete evidence to support this. What was clear, however, was that their friendship
had become obsessive. Parental concerns and separation, by 1954, the parents of both girls
had become increasingly worried about the unhealthy closeness of their relationship.
Juliet's parents were particularly concerned, especially as they were going through their
own marital difficulties. That year Henry Hume resigned from his position as rector
and plan at take Juliet back to England. Leaving behind his wife Hilda and New Zealand,
Pauline's parents were equally alarmed by the impending separation, believing it would be
best for the two girls to spend time apart. Pauline, however, was devastated by the thought
of Juliet leaving. She became increasingly resentful of her mother, Honora, whom she believed
was standing in the way of her being with Juliet. The two girls began to devise a plan, a
on the 22nd of June 1954, Pauline and Juliet lowered Pauline's mother to Victoria Park in
Christchurch under the pretext of a pleasant walk. Unbeknownst to Honora, the girls had brought with
them a half brick, wrapped in a stocking. As they walked along a secluded path,
they attacked Honora, bludgeoning her repeatedly until she died from severe head injuries.
It was a gruesome and cold blooded act, one that shocked not only the people of Christchurch,
but the entire world when news of the murder broke, the police quickly pieced together what
had happened. Both girls were arrested and, during their subsequent interrogation, freely
admitted to the murder, their diaries provided further damning evidence Pauline had written
extensively about their plan and the days leading up to the crime. In one entry, she coldly stated,
The happy vent has taken place. All went according to plan, trial and sentencing.
The trial of Pauline Parker and Juliet Hume took place in August 1954 and was a media sensation.
The public was fascinated by the seemingly privileged and intelligent girls who had committed
such a brutal murder during the trial. The defense argued that the girls were suffering from a folly
a dirt-shared psychotic disorder that had caused them to lose touch with reality. The prosecution,
however, painted a picture of cold, calculated murder driven by their desire to be together
without the interference of Pauline's mother. Ultimately, both girls were found guilty,
but due to their young age Pauline was sixteen and Juliet fifteen.
They were not sentenced to death. Instead, they were sentenced to be detained at Her Majesty's
pleasure, a term used for indefinite imprisonment. The girls were separated and sent to different
prisons, and they would never see each other again. Life after prison, Pauline and Juliet
were both released from prison after serving around five years, under strict conditions
that they never contact each other again. Upon release, they disappeared from the public eye,
adopting new identities and living quiet private lives. Pauline Parker took the name
Hillary Nathan and lived a reclusive life in England. Working as a writing instructor,
she reportedly became deeply religious and expressed remorse for her actions, though she
has never publicly spoken about the murder. Juliet Hume, on the other hand, reinvented
herself as in Perry and went on to become a successful crime novelist under this name.
She wrote numerous best-selling detective novels and only reluctantly acknowledged
her past when it was revealed by the media in the 1990s, while Perry has expressed regret
for the murder. She has also stated that she has paid for her crime and does not feel the need
to discuss it publicly. Cultural legacy, the story of Pauline Parker and Juliet Hume
has remained a source of fascination for decades. The case has been the subject of numerous books,
documentaries, and even a film Heavenly Creatures 1994, directed by Peter Jackson,
brought the story to a new generation and remains a landmark to fiction of their intense
friendship and the murder that followed. The case continues to raise questions about the nature
of obsessive relationships, the vulnerability of adolescence, and the fine line between fantasy
and reality. It also poses a darker question. Could the intense bond between Pauline and Juliet
have been controlled, or were they always destined to spiral into tragedy? The story of Pauline
Parker and Juliet Hume remains one of New Zealand's most infamous criminal cases.
What began as an intense friendship spiraled into a murder that stunned the world. Though both
women have served their time and moved on with their lives, the crime they committed
continues to intrigue, puzzle, and horrify in equal measure. Their case serves as a chilling
reminder of the destructive power of obsessive relationships and the dark turns that even
the closest of friendships can take.