Okay. Let's unpack this. We're diving deep today into the strange and pretty unsettling
case of Alyssa Zinger. It's a situation that, well, based on the sources we've looked at,
started with what seemed like a minor incident. Right. But it just unraveled fast into something
far more serious. Yeah, it really did. And for this deep dive, we've pulled from,
you know, a whole range of sources. Police reports, arrest affidavits, court documents.
Statements from law enforcement, too, again. Exactly. And even parts of body cam footage
that were presented in court, plus public reactions, commentary, and some research on the
impact, the devastating impact of this type of abuse. So our mission today is to guide you
through this. Yeah. We want to lay out the, well, the complex allegations, trace the timeline as
best we can from the documents, examine the different perspectives these sources present,
because they really do conflict in places, you know? They do. And explore the implications
of everything that's come to light so far. And it all begins quite unexpectedly, doesn't it?
Back on July 25th, 2023, the initial event was shoplifting. A Nordstrom in Tampa Bay, Florida,
involved a girl and her 13-year-old boyfriend. And here's the first moment where, you know,
reading through the reports, you kind of get a sense something isn't quite right.
When the officers asked the girl her age, she identified herself as Alyssa Zinger, said
she was 14, even give a birth date, January 1st, 2009. But the police system check,
it flagged something different. When they ran Alyssa Zinger, it came back with a 22-year-old,
Alyssa Ann Zinger. The date of birth just didn't line up at all. Not even close.
And she had an explanation, apparently. Right. She reportedly told the officers
the 22-year-old was her half-sister. But the sources show the name itself,
Alyssa Zinger versus Alyssa Ann Zinger, wasn't a perfect match either. And that age gap,
obviously huge. Yeah, a big red flag. But despite that,
the reports indicate she was allowed to leave. With the boy and his father.
Yep, allowed to leave the scene that day with the boy and his father.
For that shoplifting incident, it kind of seemed to end there.
Okay. But the truth about who she really was, that came out later.
Uh-huh. About four months later, November 24th, 2023, she was arrested again.
But this time, for something much, much more serious, a grave alleged crime.
Exactly. It was then confirmed she was indeed Alyssa Zinger.
But 22 years old, not 14, employed part-time at Publix.
And the alleged reason for lying about her age back in July?
Well, according to the affidavits, it was because she was allegedly in a relationship
with a child. The same 13-year-old boy from the shoplifting?
The very same one. That's the allegation.
Wow. Okay.
That was really striking, as the sources lay it out,
is how she allegedly connected with these young people initially.
Right.
Affidavits states she befriended students at Woodrow Wilson Middle School,
using platforms like TikTok and Snapchat.
And she didn't just connect. The reports claim she built this whole persona online.
Yeah. Presenting herself as a 14-year-old, homeschooled.
Okay.
And this online mass grade, this allegedly led to an inappropriate relationship
with one particular boy from that school.
And the timeline, the alleged timeline of their relationship.
The documents say they met in person late May 2023.
That's right. Late May.
And reportedly dated until mid-September 2023.
So about four months.
And during that period, the affidavit is pretty explicit.
It says she reportedly sent explicit images and videos of herself
to this victim using Snapchat.
Okay. So fast forward a bit.
October, after her alleged relationship with that first boy ended,
another incident happened involving him.
He had reportedly slept with a female minor.
Right. And that encounter was recorded on his phone.
Okay.
And sources indicate Alyssa allegedly found out about this video, learned it existed.
Which then led her to allegedly take steps to get it.
That's what the reports describe.
Going to the boy's home, claiming she needed to charge her phone,
kind of using that as an excuse to get inside.
Right.
And when she was in, the boy apparently went to the bathroom, left his phone unlocked.
And according to the court documents, she allegedly grabbed that chance.
Seized the moment, yeah.
Allegedly took his phone, recorded the intimate video right off his camera roll.
But it didn't stop there, did it?
With just taking the video.
No. The boy claimed, and this is documented,
that Alyssa then sent this video out.
To who?
To several of his classmates.
And also to the female minor who was in the video, again using Snapchat.
Okay. And the alleged motive.
Why would she do that?
The boy claimed it was jealousy.
Because their relationship had ended,
and this was like an attempt to get back at him, retaliation.
Wow. Now this, this is where things escalate really fast
and lead straight to her first arrest, right?
Exactly. The video circulating?
No.
That had immediate and serious consequences.
Students at the school reportedly saw it.
And they reported it.
Reported it to school staff.
And the school.
Their response, as described, was immediate.
Decisive. They called law enforcement right away.
Which started the investigation.
And led directly to her arrest on November 24, 2023.
And it was after this arrest that the Tampa Police Chief,
Lee Burkaw, made that statement, December 1, 2023.
Yeah. The sources quote him saying,
It is disturbing and unsettling to see an adult take advantage of a child and prey on them.
And her initial charges from the criminal report?
Seven felony counts.
Two for lascivious battery.
Five for lascivious solicitation.
And those charges specifically apply when the defendant is over 18
and the victim is, what, 12 to 15?
That's right. 12 to 15 years old.
So, seven serious felonies.
Okay. So, she's arrested on these seven felonies.
And here's where the public reaction really kicks in,
based on the commentary and our sources.
Right.
Shortly after that first arrest, she was bailed out.
Like, really quickly.
Which, seven hours later, yeah, bailed out of jail.
And the bond about?
It was set at $7,500 for each charge.
Seven charges, so.
Yeah.
$52,500 total.
And the public commentary on that was pretty strong, wasn't it?
A lot of outrage, fear, people worried she was just walking free,
might prey on others.
There was also talk commentary about a perceived double standard.
Comparisons to how a male suspect might be treated in a similar situation.
Right. Some suggesting a man wouldn't have gotten bail,
wouldn't have been released, especially, you know,
given Florida's stance on crimes against children.
Yeah, if that point was raised.
And then kind of jarringly, the sources also included
some really dismissive online comments.
Yeah, those were disturbing.
Commentary that seemed to downplay how serious this was,
just because the alleged victims were teenage boys,
bringing up like hormones or sexual curiosity.
And we need to be crystal clear here,
reflecting the victim impact research we saw.
Adolescence, hormones, curiosity.
None of that makes a minor less of a victim.
Absolutely not.
It doesn't justify or excuse inappropriate behavior by an adult.
The responsibility always 100% lies with the adult.
And the impact is devastatingly real.
The sources included perspectives from male survivors of abuse by women.
Yeah.
They described severe long-term effects, panic attacks,
nightmares, flinching, stuff that deeply impacts future relationships,
even brain chemistry.
Yes, and that aligns with an NCBI study mentioned in the materials.
It indicates both male and female victims of female perpetrators
can face profound long-term issues, substance abuse,
depression, rage, strained relationships with women.
Self-concept issues, identity problems.
Right.
Discomfort with intimacy later in life.
It's serious.
The fundamental principle holds true no matter the gender.
A minor can never consent to sex with an adult, period.
Exactly.
The abuse of that power, imbalance.
The consequences can be just devastating and last a lifetime.
So the investigation continues after that first arrest,
and more information starts coming out from the initial boy victim.
Yeah.
He reportedly told officers that Alyssa had admitted to him,
admitted having intimate relations with other minors, too.
Which prompted Chief Burkha to make that public appeal.
Right.
Encouraging any other potential victims to come forward.
And the media echoed that, you know, urging parents to talk to their kids,
contact police if there had been any contact with her.
And that actually worked.
More alleged victims came forward.
It did.
Not long after her first arrest, yeah.
Four more alleged victims.
Reportedly between 12 and 14.
All from the same middle school.
Wow.
Four more.
And we saw some details from their accounts and the sources.
One boy claimed Alyssa approached him on TikTok first,
then they moved to Snapchat.
Met in person.
Met in person, and things became physical.
Another alleged a movie date,
then an intimate encounter at an apartment.
So these new allegations, they led directly to her being arrested again.
Rearrested, yes.
On April 4th, 2024.
And with that second arrest came more charges.
A lot more.
Seven additional charges, bringing the total up to 14 felonies.
14.
Okay, what were the new ones?
Well, five more counts of lascivious solicitation.
Six more of lascivious battery.
So that's 11 of those total now.
But also one count of possession of CP child pornography.
One count of in-state transmission of CP by electronic device.
And one count of cyber harassment.
So the charges really escalated.
Massively.
But maybe one of the most striking and unexpected developments,
according to the sources, was the accusation that Alyssa's own parents
allegedly interfered with the investigation.
Interfered how?
Trying to protect her.
That's the allegation, deliberately.
Specifically, after the first arrest,
police got a warrant to search the parents home for Alyssa's cell phone.
Right.
When they asked for the phone,
her father allegedly handed over her mother's phone instead.
No way.
That's what's alleged.
And body cam footage, presented in court,
reportedly showed the officers struggling to figure out if the phone they were given was Alyssa's.
What did they notice?
It seemed to be out of battery.
Maybe put in airplane mode.
Just looks suspicious.
And when they asked for the passcode?
Both parents reportedly said they didn't know it.
And the judge commented on this.
Yeah.
Judge Laura Ward.
At the pre-trial detention hearing, April 8, 2024, according to reports,
she expressed significant concern, said the parents' actions hindered the investigation,
helped their daughter evade accountability.
She said they compounded the situation, made it worse.
Exactly those words.
And the public reaction to that news, the parents' alleged involvement.
Intense anger, based on the commentary we saw,
people questioning why they hadn't been charged with obstruction.
Right, the Florida statute for tampering with evidence was brought up third degree felony.
Yeah, 918.13, punishable by up to five years, $5K fine.
That was part of the public discussion.
So we also get another glimpse into the family's perspective from more body cam footage.
Right, showing the parents interacting with officers outside their home another time.
And this is where the father made that, what the source called a startling statement.
Yes, he allegedly placed the blame squarely on the victim.
Quote of this saying, she got messed up with the wrong kid.
Blaming the victim, wow.
Yeah, the reports detail his arguments.
Calling the victim insane, contrasting his daughter claims she was never in trouble,
a virgin till 21, a perfect angel.
With the victim's alleged lifestyle, describing him as 14 with girlfriends over,
making videos, make out sessions.
Right, that was his reported narrative.
And the public reaction to those comments.
Disgust, mostly.
Commentary calling him delusional.
Indenial, blaming a minor victim.
Some even speculated if he might be complicit somehow.
And his comments also hinted at a possible defense strategy,
mentioning she has problems and mental issues.
Exactly, which was echoed in court by her defense attorney, Data Hersey Fullgera.
Okay, what did the defense argue?
Reportedly argued, Alyssa has significant developmental issues,
emotional issues, low self-esteem, history of being bullied.
They showed family photos of her without eyelashes.
Yeah, allegedly as evidence of emotional struggles.
Noted she was in special ed, switched high schools.
The argument being that the text messages weren't between equals.
Right, that she was an adult interacting with kids
through the lens of her own alleged developmental issues.
That was the defense's angle.
But the prosecutor pushed back.
Strongly, argued her school records showed no signs of developmental delay,
and contended that, you know, any alleged mental health issues
don't excuse misrepresenting her age or targeting child victims.
Okay, then there was another fascinating moment on body cam.
When police went back in January 2024 to photograph her bedroom.
Yes.
And the father made another confession called startling.
Yeah, quite emotional apparently.
He said the arrest, while awful, hadn't been entirely negative,
stating they finally got our daughter back.
Meaning what?
Described her now playing, watching TV, hanging out with them.
Added she wouldn't have a phone again.
And the public commentary on that confession.
Questioned if his sort of coddling might have contributed.
Some suggesting his treatment made her feel like she was 14, enabling the behavior.
And Alyssa's own attitude during that bedroom search.
The footage reportedly showed her expressing frustration.
Annoyed about pictures being taken that police showed up without calling.
Feeling the treatment didn't fit the crime.
Like she felt like a murderer.
Something like that, yeah.
Seems largely dismissive of the police being there.
Okay, so let's summarize the alleged victims based on the sources.
Total is currently five male minors.
That's right.
The initial 13-year-old plus four more boys aged 12 to 14, all from the same school.
And we have to remember the allegation about stealing and distributing the CP
involving the female minor.
Right.
Which adds another layer.
Suggest potential danger to young girls too.
So where does the case stand now, legally speaking?
Well, as of our last look at the sources, there's still no trial date set.
So no official verdict yet.
And the potential sentence if convicted on all 14 counts?
It's huge.
Up to 266 years potentially.
Yeah.
Sentences run consecutively.
Basically life.
Though, you know, sources note plea agreements or other factors could change that.
And her current status?
Where is she?
She remains in jail.
Held without bail since that second arrest back in April 2024.
And the judge's reason for denying bail back in April.
Was pretty clear, according to reports.
Judge Ward stated the core issue wasn't who first recorded that video.
Right.
But that she, as an adult, was allegedly in multiple videos with young boys,
13 and 14, manipulating them, taking advantage.
That was the judge's focus.
Have there been more attempts to get her released on bond?
Yes, subsequent attempts.
For instance, at a June 3, 2024 court appearance,
defense argued for release again, citing her alleged psychological issues,
saying she's not a normal 22-year-old.
But the state opposed it.
Strongly.
Hillsborough County prosecutor Tracy Dishman argued, as noted in the sources,
that there are no conditions of release reasonably sufficient to protect the community
from the risk of physical harms to persons, specifically males under 18.
And she's in protective custody in jail.
Reports mention that, yeah.
Apparently to prevent her using standard inmate tablets for communication.
Concern about social media access, maybe contacting others.
Okay, so as you can see, this case, it's really far from over.
Not at all.
Investigators reportedly believe there could still be more victims out there who haven't come forward yet.
Which means the full scope, the full impact of her alleged actions, it's still uncertain.
So we've tried to walk you through the key elements of this
deeply complex and troubling case of Alyssa Zimmer.
Yeah, from that initial shoplifting and the alleged age lie.
To the really disturbing details of online targeting.
The alleged relationships with multiple minors.
That whole video incident is the alleged theft and distribution.
Right.
And the serious accusations about her family's alleged involvement interfering with the investigation.
And just the ongoing complex legal process itself.
So thinking about all these different accounts of perspectives we've touched on,
from the sources, you know, the alleged actions.
The defense claims about mental issues.
The father blaming the victim.
Yeah, all those conflicting layers.
What stands out to you the most?
About the complexities and the different viewpoints in this case.
Something to think about.
Definitely a lot to consider.
Thanks for joining us for this deep dive.