Okay, let's dive in.
We're unpacking a story today that feels like it could, well, it could only really happen
in the age of online influence.
It really does.
Our source material is a detailed YouTube transcript.
It chronicles the life of Kat Torres from her challenging beginnings to becoming
this viral online personality, life coach, spiritual guru, and then ultimately facing
some really serious allegations.
That's right.
The sources you shared, they allow this whole narrative that starts with like overcoming
hardship, building this huge online following, projecting this super luxurious lifestyle.
And then it shifts pretty dramatically to these deeply disturbing claims, manipulation, exploitation,
even human trafficking, made by people really close to her.
So our mission here in this deep dive is to basically go through this source material,
try to understand the narrative it presents, look at the tactics that we're allegedly
used, explore the reported ripple effects on our followers, and just think about the
bigger picture, you know, the implications of online influence.
And it's crucial everything we discuss comes only from the sources you've provided.
We're sticking just to that.
Exactly.
Just the source material.
It's a story that takes us from, well, what looks like ambition and resilience to
something much, much darker, allegedly.
Absolutely.
So where did the sources say her story really begins?
What was her background like?
Okay, so the sources tell us Cat Torres, born in Balem, Brazil, back in 1992, grew up in
poverty, apparently had an alcoholic father, so, you know, a really tough start.
Yeah, sounds like it.
But despite that, her looks got noticed early on.
Right.
She got into modeling, beauty pageants, starting when she was just what, 12?
Yeah, 12 years old.
And even in that world, the sources mentioned she experienced assault by men involved
in the pageants.
Oh, wow.
And they note that this reportedly shaped her leader life pretty significantly.
It's clear she was determined, though.
She pushed through that achieved some early success, won the Miss Kyer's Walk, got signed
with elite modeling.
Right.
Traveled in Europe the whole thing.
And then she got a big dose of public attention.
The sources mentioned her being spotted with Leonardo DiCaprio.
Uh, yes, that story.
Now Cat never confirmed it.
He denied it later.
But the sources are pretty clear.
That moment definitely boosted her fame.
You could see, or the sources suggest you could see, a real hunger for stardom there.
And this is where the sources show her making a conscious shift, right?
Moving to America, changing careers.
Exactly.
Leveraging that modeling fame to sort of rebrand herself as a businesswoman, an
influencer.
She was already kind of known on social media.
And she built on it by sharing personal stuff.
Her routine, fitness, self-improvement.
The sources say this felt really relatable, very authentic to people.
And that perceived authenticity, well, it's gold online, isn't it?
Totally.
It really worked for her.
Built her Instagram to over a million followers.
The sources call them die-hard fans.
And she pivots again.
Becomes a life coach.
Right.
And the message was powerful because it was simple, tied to her story.
If I can do it, so can you.
Which, you know, if you bought into the online persona, seemed pretty credible.
She offered courses, dating advice, one-on-one coaching.
Yeah, the sources say up to $700 a session.
OK.
But this rapid rise, this online success, it started raising questions, according
to the sources, especially around her wealth.
The lifestyle she was showing up.
Exactly.
Super extravagant, luxury vacations, this huge NYC apartment, views of the Hudson, Statue
of Liberty, the works.
And the sources specifically ask, you know, could her modeling savings really fund
all that?
There was speculation brewing.
Yeah.
And her former roommate, Luzer Torsky, he's quoted in the sources, said he wasn't
paying for their flat and he didn't think Kat was either.
He even described picking up an envelope stuffed with cash for her.
Right.
So the sources flip this idea that maybe she wasn't quite the self-made
woman she claimed.
They mentioned speculation she was a sugar baby.
And that rumored Russian oligarch, A.
Yeah, A. Allegedly funding her lifestyle, supposed connections to Putin, gifts
like a diamond Rolex.
It definitely clashes with the image she's sold to her followers and coaching
clients.
It's a pretty big discrepancy, the sources point out, suggests that core
message might have been, well, built on shaky ground.
And then things take another major turn, according to the sources, a health crisis.
Yeah, this is huge.
She comes back from Brazil, contracts a flesh-eating disease, really serious
stuff.
Required removing implants, eventually her left breast.
And she documented this whole ordeal intensely on social media.
But the sources suggest that this health crisis, the physical changes,
maybe led to losing those rich suitors.
Including the alleged Russian boyfriend, she reportedly felt abandoned.
Yeah, that's what the sources say.
And that feeling of vulnerability, it seems like that was a catalyst for,
well, a new direction.
Superiority.
Specifically, ayahuasca.
Okay.
But the sources are specific.
They say after these ayahuasca experiences, she flipped, started
going off the deep end.
And this is when she started claiming the spiritual gift, the voice.
Yes, according to her, or according to the sources reporting on her,
this voice gave her insights, predicted the future.
Which is what shifted her from life coach to, like, spiritual guru territory.
And the sources immediately kind of posed the question,
was this a real spiritual awakening?
Or were these, and they used the phrase, troubling delusions?
The sources also mentioned some key influences around this time.
Yeah, like the Brazilian psychic, John of God.
Who was later convicted of sexual assault.
Right, and also Tony Robbins.
Kat's husband apparently said she dragged him to their events.
They also spent time back in Brazil exploring different religious practices.
The sources describe it as her looking for an answer.
Becoming really deeply invested in spiritualism,
which apparently caused a lot of strain in her marriage to Colburn.
She even wrote a book, didn't she?
The Voice.
Yeah, claiming the whole thing came to her in a trance.
And the sources detail some of the stuff she said she was getting from The Voice,
hearing messages from other planets.
Uh-huh.
Information, civilization isn't prepared for, talk about death.
Again, the sources really frame these as potentially troubling delusions.
And this seems to be where the sources indicate the alleged harm really starts to surface.
Her behavior reportedly got aggressive, hostile.
Straining the marriage with Colburn even more.
And then there's Anna.
Right, the sources describe Kat persuading Anna, who was a client from Boston,
to move in with her in New York.
And the offer sounded like a real job, right?
$2,000 a month.
Yeah, to care for pets, cook, do laundry, seem straightforward.
But the reality, according to the sources,
totally different from the online image.
The house was apparently a mess.
Kat peed on the sofas.
That's what Anna reportedly said.
And described Kat herself as strange.
And demanding constant companionship.
Even in the shower.
Apparently so.
Anna described trying to get sleep by, like pretending to go to the gym,
but actually just sleeping on a yoga mat somewhere else in the building.
Saying she was afraid Kat would come after me,
as she just tried to sleep in her room.
That's intense.
And the kicker.
The sources say Anna was never actually paid.
Never paid.
Nope.
And when she asked for the money, Kat allegedly got aggressive
and apparently brought up some really dark,
traumatic memories of domestic violence for Anna.
Just awful stuff.
Wow.
So Anna managed to get out after three months.
Yeah, but it reportedly took her over a year to fully cut off communication.
The sources really point to Kat's alleged control tactics
making it hard to break free.
Meanwhile, back with the husband, Coburn,
before he could file for divorce, Kat just vanished.
Seemingly, he ended up hiring a PI to find her.
And the sources say that in 2022,
Kat, who was 30 by then, moved to Texas
with a new husband, Zach, who was only 21.
Yeah, quite an age gap there.
They move into this big five-bedroom house.
And this is where the sources introduced the witch clan.
Right.
Kat allegedly reaches out to loyal Brazilian followers online,
says she's having a mental health crisis,
needs them to come join her in Texas.
And the offer she made them.
Sounded amazing according to the sources,
personal access to the voice, free rent,
paid flights, and $2,000 a month salary.
So the sources name three women who took her up on it.
Leticia, Desiree, and someone called Soul.
Yeah, Soul is an alias.
The sources describe them as vulnerable women
who trusted Kat, saw it as a huge opportunity.
Desiree, for instance, apparently believed
Kat had healed her migraines.
OK.
And she asked Kat for advice about her marriage problems.
Kat allegedly told her to just leave her husband
and come work with her instead.
And Kat called them her witch clan.
That's the term the sources use.
Apparently Kat got heavily into witchcraft around this time,
had a dedicated room, an altar.
Used for spiritual advice based on what she said
or what the voice said.
Exactly.
And a chilling example the sources give.
Desiree was reportedly told by the voice
to go find her husband at a strip club.
What?
Yeah.
So she went and then she started working there herself
using the name Chanel.
And the sources emphasize these women allegedly
followed Kat's orders, like whether they wanted to or not.
That's the picture painted, yes.
OK, let's dig into that Texas house situation more.
The sources describe some really disturbing stuff
about exploitation and control.
Yeah, it gets pretty dark.
The sources detail major financial control.
Kat paid for their flights, housing, food, sure.
But allegedly insisted they couldn't leave
until they paid her back every penny.
Reportedly even threatened to curse them if they tried.
Wow.
And there was a hierarchy.
Oh yeah.
Kat at the top, the queen, sometimes even Mother Mary.
Zack, the young husband, was like, God.
And the women at the very bottom.
And any money the women earned.
Allegedly went straight to Kat, all of it.
Including everything Desiree made working at the strip club.
And Kat said income targets.
Dealing targets, yeah.
Started at $1,000 a day, then apparently went even higher.
How did she justify this?
The sources say she claimed she couldn't work
because of her health issues.
And Zack needed to stay home to focus on his MMA training.
MMA training.
Apparently the voice predicted he'd make millions.
And Desiree was reportedly paying for his trainer too.
Unbelievable.
And the sources say Kat set up online profiles for them.
Seating profiles, yeah.
Including on Sugar Baby and escort sites
for Desiree and Letitia.
And raised Desiree's target to $3,000 a day.
That's what the sources claim.
And if she didn't make it,
forced to sleep outside, allegedly.
Plus threats of calling the police if they didn't comply.
This level of control, it's staggering.
The law of silence.
Yeah, the sources describe that too.
Women reportedly forbidden from speaking to each other,
couldn't even leave their rooms,
not even for the bathroom without Kat's permission.
This sounds like psychological torture.
And the sources say the coaching they received shifted.
Started normalizing sex work, SW.
How so?
Kat reportedly tried to tempt Desiree,
comparing how much she could earn.
And Sol, the other woman, overheard Kat,
allegedly telling a client that she herself
was punished by the voice to be an SW in Brazil.
Okay, hearing that conversation,
that's what pushed Sol to escape.
That's what the sources indicate, yeah.
She overheard that and started planning.
Managed to get out after 42 days,
apparently with help from an ex-boyfriend.
But she was still scared.
Terrified, the sources emphasize.
Because Kat allegedly had their documents,
passports, birth certificates, everything.
And Zak was known to be well-armed,
reportedly talked about it openly.
So Desiree, she was still there.
And she eventually agreed to start SW.
Yes.
The sources reference her book,
Searching Desiree, where she talks about it.
Her first time charging $1,000.
And the fear she lived with.
Constant fear, she reportedly described.
Fear of arrest, immigration problems even being killed,
said she'd scrub herself raw after encounters.
And all that money, straight to Kat.
Every cent, according to the sources.
And the sources mentioned something
about their appearance changing.
Yeah, a really striking detail.
Kat reportedly dyed the women's hair blonde.
Desiree started wearing contacts.
The sources suggest it was like
she was turning them into her clones.
Wow.
Okay, so this whole situation,
it eventually breaks into public view, right?
April 2022.
Exactly.
The sources say Kat went online
and launched this just vicious public attack
on her former assistant, Anna.
The one who escaped from New York.
That's the one.
Reportedly called her a traitor,
made a really bizarre threat about her skull placement.
That's a skull placement.
Yeah, demanded followers, tag Anna,
called her a slave, just completely unhinged stuff,
according to the sources.
And that online outburst
is what finally got police attention,
or at least prompted Anna and Sol to file reports.
Yes, although the sources say initially
the police didn't take the reports that seriously.
But then things escalated in Brazil.
Massively.
September 2022, the families of Desiree and Letitia
back in Brazil file missing persons reports.
They'd lost all contact.
And that blew up in the media there?
Huge coverage in Brazil, the sources say.
Suddenly there was widespread public concern
about Kat Torres.
And another alleged victim came forward then too,
about being scammed.
Yeah, sources mentioned someone else
claiming they were scammed out of a lot of money.
While all this is happening, Kat's on vacation,
defending herself online.
Apparently.
And then Desiree and Letitia post these videos.
The ones where they say they want to be there?
Yeah, claiming they wanted to live with Kat,
basically turning against their families
to show loyalty to Kat.
Although Letitia later reportedly took back
the things she said about her father in those videos.
But people watching saw red flags.
Big time, according to the sources.
The women talked about Kat like she was some kind of god
capable of saving the world, mentioning Zuckerberg, Putin.
In disconnected phrases.
That's how the sources describe it.
Leading to speculation was it ayahuasca, hypnosis,
manipulation.
The Brazilian paper O Globo apparently said
they looked drugged.
Then external people started trying to intervene.
Yeah.
Like that Brazilian model Yasmin Brunette.
Yeah, she has a huge following.
She joined one of Letitia's Instagram lives,
asked her straight up,
film the room, show us you're not being threatened.
How did Letitia react?
Kat irritated, ended the live stream
pretty quick, sources say.
And later Desiree and Letitia
actually accused Yasmin of a crime.
A crime Kat was supposedly guilty of.
Exactly.
Yasmin filed a police complaint over it.
Letitia later reportedly explained
why they did it basically.
To show Yasmin what it felt like to be falsely accused,
hoping it would make people stop
calling the police on Kat.
Because the police were getting overwhelmed?
Yeah.
Sources indicate they were swamped with calls by them.
Okay.
So when did the police really start taking
the trafficking allegations seriously?
The sources say it was when they found
those online escort profiles for Letitia and Desiree
and they listed Kat's actual address in Texas.
That's pretty concrete.
Yeah.
And right after that,
the group apparently fled Texas, headed up to Maine.
And the stuff left behind in the Texas house?
Found by a neighbor, hoodoo dolls, herbs.
The neighbor described them as unusual,
mentioned some were apparently for exorcisms,
really weird stuff.
And the past victims like Anna
contacting the FBI, they kept pushing.
They didn't give up according to the sources.
As things heated up, Kat lashed out more,
even at her husband's father.
Yeah, allegedly saying really disturbing things like,
when you die, I hope you lessen.
Just seem to be spiraling.
So the police finally catch up with them in Maine.
They make contact.
Call Kat while she's apparently on the road
with Letitia and Desiree.
And they try to check on the girls.
Yeah, officers asking things like,
liking America safe and sound,
trying to gauge the situation.
The sources say the girls stayed loyal during that call.
But there was a recording.
This is key according to the sources.
Kat was secretly recorded before that police call,
apparently threatening the girls,
telling them how to behave, what to say.
Okay, that changes things.
Definitely.
An officer then persuaded Kat
to bring the girls down to the police station in Maine.
And the detectives noticed their behavior.
Yeah, they observed Letitia and Desiree
were extremely closed off
and distrusting of law enforcement.
The sources note this is actually common
in trafficking victims.
And Kat herself.
Reportedly very evasive.
Avoided direct answers about her job
or what exactly the girls did for her.
So based on everything they gathered.
Authorities concluded Kat was involved
in trafficking and exploitation.
The sources say they recognized
textbook trafficking tactics.
Like gaining trust,
then isolating them financially and socially.
Exactly.
They also found out she'd overstayed her visa.
Which led to her deportation.
Back to Brazil, yeah.
Where she was immediately arrested,
charged with human trafficking, slave labor,
medical fraud.
And the first trial focused just
on Desiree's allegations.
That's right.
While she was waiting for that verdict in 2024,
she gave that BBC interview from prison.
Yeah, and the sources detail what she said.
It's pretty revealing.
She claimed she was different from other inmates.
Totally. Called it real jail
with real people that committed real crimes
mentioned people who killed like 10 people
trying to distance herself.
And she denied everything.
All the allegations, all the victim testimony.
Flat out denied it according to the sources.
Said there were so many lies she couldn't stop laughing.
Actually claimed she thought she'd be out in 20 days.
Her explanation for why the judge kept her detained.
Was pretty out there.
Claimed people said she was a problem outside.
Someone who could take the minds of the people
and change them.
Which led her to question if she was a fraud or dangerous.
Yeah, like a fake guru versus so real and dangerous.
She reportedly even said she saw herself as a danger
because she could change minds asking,
she can too, can you, can I, I hope I can.
It's bizarre.
And she denied the women ever lived with her.
Denied it completely.
Said other than my dog.
Denied sending messages inviting them.
Denied the bank transfers from Desiree were paychecks.
Claimed they were for Uber rides.
Yeah.
Like three, four K a month in Ubers.
That was her explanation according to the sources.
Denied the post about Anna's skull.
Denied Anna ever worked for her or lived with her.
Denied it all.
And she called the claims of PTSD
from former clients absolutely ridiculous.
Said they should run back to their parents.
Claimed her advice was perfect.
That she was born with all talents.
Just zero self-awareness apparent in the interview
based on the sources.
And accountability.
Zero.
That was her word according to the sources.
Maintained she didn't deserve prison.
Said you choose to believe
whatever you choose to believe.
I can tell you I'm Jesus and you can see Jesus
or you can see the devil.
And then after the interview, she threatened the reporter.
Caught on camera saying she didn't like her.
Just couldn't help herself it seems.
Well the judge wasn't buying it.
Not at all.
The sources report she was sentenced to eight years
for the human trafficking and slavery of Desiree.
And that sentence plus her total lack of remorse
in that interview, it caused outrage.
Yeah, the sources say people were furious.
Calls for much harsher sentences,
even life in prison, which is possible for trafficking.
And the whole case sparked a bigger conversation.
Definitely.
About social media's impact,
the dangers of idolizing strangers online,
societal values, how women's insecurities
get turned into a business,
mentioning platforms like TikTok even.
Concerns about Zach, the husband too.
Not facing charges.
Yeah, the sources note concern that he,
described as an accomplice and known to be armed,
didn't face legal consequences.
But investigations are ongoing in Brazil.
That's what the sources state.
Into other allegations against cat tours.
So potentially more prison time down the road.
For some victims though,
the conviction itself is a step towards healing.
It seems so.
One victim is quoted saying they feel better
because I know she's in jail.
Hoping more victims feel safe enough to come forward now.
But others still feel unsafe.
Even with the judge banning her
from the internet post release.
Yeah, the fear is real according to the sources.
The feeling that she'll just re-offend,
as one source put it,
rules never stopped cat tours before.
A feeling she'll do it again whenever she gets out.
So we've really walked through the sources here.
From cat tours is challenging start,
her rise to viral fame.
And then peeling back these layers
of alleged manipulation, exploitation,
all reportedly hidden under that shiny online persona.
Yeah, we've looked at the tactics described,
the devastating impact reported for the women involved,
the legal side covered in the sources,
and these lingering fears and questions.
The information presented about the power of influence online
and the vulnerability it can create, it's really stark.
It really is how trust built on this carefully crafted image
can allegedly be turned into a weapon.
So consider all these vivid,
often-disturbing details from the sources.
It leaves you, the listener,
with a pretty big question, doesn't it?
How do we as people consuming online content
looking for connection or inspiration,
how do we get better at navigating that tricky space
between genuine inspiration and potential exploitation?